# **Prateek Chatterjee**

<u>prateekpc.ux@gmail.com</u> - 508-471-0199 - <u>Portfolio</u> - <u>LinkedIn</u> – <u>YouTube</u> - Arlington, VA (Willing to Relocate)

I am a Senior UX Designer with five years of experience helping clients across the federal gov., healthcare, telecom, automotive and consulting industries. Led projects successfully and leveraged business and technical skills to deliver customer focused solutions.

- Business & Market Analysis
- Roadmap Mgmt
- Data-Analytics
- Strategic Planning
- Product/ UX/ UI Design
- Agile/ Scrum Methodology
- Product Lifecycle Mgmt
- Release Documentation
- Stakeholder Mgmt
- Managing UX Team
- Training Support
- Training Implementation

#### **Professional Experience**

#### **Senior UX Designer - CGI Inc.** | *March 2022 – Present*

Received an Award in 2023 | Celebrating CGI's Values: Partnership and Quality

- Lead complex digital products applications through multiple lifecycle and complex stakeholder management.
- Ensure product meets customer needs and drive the objective of simplifying the processes.
- Responsible for managing CGI's relationship with <u>Brightspeed Business</u> by leading research & design sessions with VP and marketing team across 15 design sprints. The focus was on increasing customer acquisition while reducing customer attrition through improved CX with the launch of new products.
- Helped Brightspeed launch their brand online by migrating **50+ exiting Lumen and Centurylink webpages** & content to the new Brightspeed Business experience with a very tight deadline. Ideated and designed **15 new AEM** components to meet the new design needs.
- The Google analytics report showcased a significant boost over **47% increase** in page views, coupled with a **45% increase** in unique pageviews, and a **whopping 70% drop** in bounce rate.
- Facilitated developer meetings to comprehend coding limitations in Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) and provided feedback to streamline component development within time, resource, and dev constraints.
- Successfully migrated design system from Sketch to Figma, revamped guidelines, font system, color usage, buttons, and components across 3 breakpoints (desktop, tablet, and mobile) for consistency, reusability and new use cases.
- Led a team of 4 product analysts/ designers to design a VR experience where users can practice high stress social tasks to build skills and confidence. The initiative was to help CGI venture into XR industries.

## **UX/UI Designer - Softrams LLC.** | March 2019 - April 2022

- Led the research & design of new modules in <u>ACO Management System Medicare Shared Savings Program</u>, a Federal agency healthcare product. Designed new modules on the existing system and worked with CMS clients and end users to establish product vision and MVP features.
- Re-designed existing modules with UX research methods, also advocated for clear UX writing and 508 compliance testing (accessibility) using wave/web-aim tools. According to the <u>latest performance</u>, ACO-MS had a record year in 2019, in which users saved **\$1.2 Billion in Medicare** as compared to \$739 in 2018.
- Carried out UX Research/Design for high profile business contract, which resulted in a \$37 million program.
- Designed a file sharing and storing healthcare secure SaaS app (<u>Hdrive</u>) based on Google Material design.
- Validated design solutions by facilitating user personas, competitive analysis, wireframing, card sorting for requirement gathering, information architecture and high-fidelity prototypes.

# **UX/UI & Web Developer - Carmaguys LLC. (Co-op)** | July 2018 - Dec 2018

 Worked with developers and stakeholders to re-design the appointment & scheduling-based application for car service & repair website.

#### IT System Admin – Worcester Polytechnic Institute | January 2017 - March 2018

• Managed hardware and software issues and provided technical support to professors, students and staffs.

## Education

#### **Worcester Polytechnic Institute**

Interactive Media and Game Development, Master of Science, 2016 – 2018

<u>View Master's Thesis</u> - Designed and implemented a car driving simulator to teach driving rules and regulations, incorporating user research, A/B testing, and usability tests to enhance effectiveness and user experience.

### University of Mumbai, India

Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Science, 2011 - 2015

#### **Skills**

**UX/UI:** Design Systems, Usability Testing, User Research, Prototyping, Wireframing, 508 Compliance, Accessibility, User Flows, Affinity Diagrams, Storyboarding, Information Architecture, Competitive Analysis, A/B Testing, Interaction Design, Card Sorting, Heuristic Evaluation, User Interview & Surveys

Other: UI & Web Development, Graphic Design, 3D Modeling, VR & Game Design

#### **Tools**

**Design:** Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, Maya 3D, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, Mural, Optimal Workshop, Google Docs, Miro, Microsoft Office

Business: Jira, Confluence, Salesforce, Web Analytics (Google Analytics), Pendo, Lucidcharts

Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, C#, NodeJS

#### **Certifications**

- Certified SAFe® 6 Product Owner/ Product Manager (POPM) certificate.
- Certified SAFe® 5 Practitioner certificate
- User Experience and Interaction for AR/VR/MR/XR Certificate authorized by University of Michigan
- Foundation of User Experience (UX) Design Google UX Design Certificate
- Conduct UX Research and Test Early Subjects Google UX Design Certificate
- Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, Ideate Google UX Design Certificate
- Build wireframes and low-fidelity prototypes Google UX Design Certificate

#### YouTube channel

- Founded and managed a successful <u>Youtube channel</u> focused on comic characters, demonstrating a strong understanding of the target user's needs and interests.
- Utilized qualitative and quantitative research findings to create captivating content that resonated with viewers, resulting in approximately 3.5 million views and 8 thousand subscribers within just 6 months.
- Conducted comprehensive user research, competitive analysis, and utilized Google analytics to gain insights into audience behavior and optimize content strategy.